Moiz-Ur-Rehman Azmat

Nationality: Pakistani **Date of birth:** 16/06/1999 **\ Phone:** (+92) 3435995776

Email: moizurrehman0341@gmail.com in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/moeezrehman/

Website: https://moizurrehman.com

• Home: Islamabad (Pakistan)

ABOUT MYSELF

Experienced web developer with a strong background in developing award-winning applications for a diverse clientele. 3.5 years of industry experience includes programming, debugging, and designing. Skilled in NodeJS, Next JS, React JS, MongoDB, SQL and AWS. Team player with an eye for detail. Passionate in working, highly motivated & goal oriented with a sincere commitment to excellence.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

AIO [15/01/2024 - Current]

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

- Developing robust and scalable applications using TypeScript and NestJS, prioritizing efficiency and maintainability.
- Managing PostgreSQL databases, optimizing data storage and retrieval methods for improved performance.
- Conducting rigorous pull request reviews to ensure high code quality and adherence to best practices.
- Collaborating seamlessly with cross-functional teams, utilizing JIRA for efficient project management and task tracking.
- Leveraging AWS services to deploy, monitor, and scale applications, enhancing reliability and scalability.

Full Stack Engineer

ISMMART Group of Industries [25/10/2022 - 15/01/2024]

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

- Designed, developed, and maintained web-based applications using NodeJS, ReactJS, NextJS, MySQL, MongoDB and AWS.
- Worked on several key projects including an e-commerce platform i.e. ismmart.com, real estate portal, HR management software.
- Designing and managing database, including writing database queries and performing database optimizations.
- Analyzing project requirements and devising effective plans and solutions for their successful implementation.
- Built and maintained RESTful APIs and integrated them with front-end components.

Backend Developer

QuellxCode Pvt Ltd [19/04/2022 – 10/11/2022]

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

- Worked on an existing enterprise project.
- Developed Rest APIs for mobile, web and game applications.
- Technologies: NodeJS, MongoDB, ReactJS, Firebase, Stripe, Redis.
- · Deployments on AWS and bug fixing.

Full Stack Engineer

Tech Flickers [10/08/2021 – 24/09/2021]

City: Remote

- Design and development of web applications.
- Development using technologies like ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Firebase Integration.

Full Stack Developer

Innovativity [16/08/2021 - 24/09/2021]

City: Remote

• Updating and developing web-based applications using React|S, Dot-Net, and MySQL.

MERN Stack Developer

Freelance [01/04/2021 - 01/03/2022]

- Successfully delivered numerous full stack web applications for global clients through various freelancing platforms.
- Developed diverse solutions, including logistics portals, admin dashboards, and portfolio websites, with a focus on scalability and user experience.
- Integrated third-party APIs like Google Maps, Stripe, and PayPal for enhanced functionality.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Capital University of Science and Technology [10/09/2018 – 30/07/2022]

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan | Website: https://cust.edu.pk/

DIGITAL SKILLS

TypeScript / JavaScript / Node.js (Express.js/Nest.js) / React.js / Next JS / MySQL / PostgreSQL / MongoDB / Git/GitHub / Firebase / Docker / CSS / HTML / Python / Redis / Stripe Payments / Payment Systems / AWS EC2 / AWS S3 / AWS RDS / AWS Cognito / Data Structures / Algorithms / Micro Services / Third-party API integration

PROJECTS

[15/09/2021 - 17/07/2022]

Job Portal with CV Ranking and Online Test

Technologies: Python, Node JS, React JS, MySQL, AWS(EC2+RDS)

[01/04/2022 - 01/05/2022]

Brain Tumor Detection

• Designed a Deep Learning model which can detect if a person have brain tumor or not using MRI Images

CERTIFICATES

[01/02/2022 - 01/05/2022]

Artificial Intelligence Bootcamp (Samsung Innovation Campus)

[06/01/2020 - 06/02/2020]

Frontend Fundamentals (pirple)

[20/02/2021 - 20/03/2021]

Data Science methodology (IBM)

[01/04/2021 - 01/05/2021]

Data Analysis with python (IBM)

[18/01/2021 - 18/02/2021]

Tools for Data science (IBM)